hey everybody welcome to this b1
english listening practice video you can
use this video to practice your
listening and comprehension
as i speak before we start remember to
sign up for our one dollar listening
practice seminars at polyglossa.com
and download my free listening time
podcast
so you can practice your listening
skills
[Music]
so today i'm going to talk about
stereotypes
a stereotype is an idea or image about a
group of people
that might be true but it might also be
a little oversimplified
this is a topic that a lot of us might
find pretty funny
but some people might also get offended
when this topic comes up
my intention with this video is
definitely not to offend any of you
so i think it'd be better if i focused
on stereotypes about americans
rather than stereotypes about people
from other countries
i'll go through some of the most common
ones and then i'll give my opinion about
how accurate they actually are
so without further ado here's the first
stereotype
americans are rich this is a stereotype
that practically every american will
face at some point if they spend a
significant time abroad
as an american who's lived abroad for
years i can tell you firsthand that this
stereotype is strong
no doubt it usually isn't a big issue
but sometimes you get the feeling that
people are looking at you with
dollar signs in their eyes to me it's
kind of funny because
i'm not rich not even close yet i get
treated like this all the time
to an extent though this stereotype has
some general truth to it
the average american is definitely
better off than the average person from
most other countries
so this stereotype's complicated the
next one
is that americans don't know much about
the rest of the world
some might even use the word ignorant
when describing the average american's
knowledge
about things like names and languages of
other countries
this stereotype definitely has some
truth to it obviously there are many
americans who
are knowledgeable about other countries
but by and large the average american
doesn't know a whole lot about foreign
countries
for example many americans probably
think that brazilians speak spanish
and many americans have probably never
heard of countries like uzbekistan
or azerbaijan but let me just say this
in my experience talking to people from
all over the world
i found that most people don't really
know a whole lot about countries that
are far away from their own
it's not only americans that don't know
much about far away countries
people from other countries don't know
much either and that's natural
because we normally just pay attention
to what's relevant to our lives
for most people knowing about world
geography simply isn't that important
so yes this second stereotype is
somewhat true but i think it's also true
for people from other countries
alright here's another stereotype
americans are workaholics
a workaholic for those of you who don't
know is someone who's addicted to
working
this stereotype is an interesting one
because i can definitely see a lot of
truth to it
compared with other countries americans
work a lot and we work pretty hard
i actually like this tradition i think
that being hard working is a great trait
to have
we can obviously see the fruit of all
this labor as america has produced and
invented a lot over the years
however the negative side to this is
that some americans
are obsessed with their work their work
consumes their whole life
and they don't have time for anything
else when people take it to that extreme
it's definitely a bad thing
overall i think the stereotype of
americans being workaholics is fairly
accurate
but i also think that the work ethic is
slowly dropping over time
i think that in general our grandparents
generation probably worked a little
longer
and harder than my generation here's one
last stereotype
americans are very patriotic overall
if you compare america to other
countries this one's definitely true
obviously not everybody's patriotic but
if we consider the nation as a whole
in my opinion america is definitely the
most patriotic country
okay now i'm going to ask you three
questions about today's video
write your answers in a comment down
below number one
name three stereotypes about americans
number two
what's a workaholic and number three
in your opinion do you think americans
are very patriotic
all right before we go remember to sign
up for our one dollar listening practice
seminars
and download our free listening time
podcast
to practice your listening skills and of
course
subscribe to the channel click on the
bell and follow
us on instagram i'll see you next time
you